<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<dataset ownertag="DAM">
   <dataref>http://damocles.met.no:8080/thredds/catalog/data/SU/aoe/</dataref>
   <drpath>DAMOC/aoe</drpath>
   <product_name>AOE-2001 dataset</product_name>
   <area>Arctic Ocean</area>
   <northernmost_latitude>90</northernmost_latitude>
   <contact>michaelt@misu.su.se</contact>
   <topiccategory>climatologyMeteorologyAtmosphere</topiccategory>
   <PI_name>Michael Tjernstrom</PI_name>
   <keywords>Polar</keywords>
   <keywords>Troposphere</keywords>
   <keywords>Meteorological Observation</keywords>
   <keywords>Measurement</keywords>
   <keywords>Atmospheric Boundary Layer</keywords>
   <keywords>Clouds</keywords>
   <keywords>Remote Sensing</keywords>
   <keywords>Soundings</keywords>
   <keywords>Temperature</keywords>
   <keywords>Humidity</keywords>
   <keywords>Wind</keywords>
   <keywords>Pressure</keywords>
   <keywords>Turbulence</keywords>
   <keywords>Radiation</keywords>
   <keywords>Visibility</keywords>
   <westernmost_longitude>-10</westernmost_longitude>
   <activity_type>Cruise</activity_type>
   <project_name>AOE-2001</project_name>
   <Conventions>CF-1.0</Conventions>
   <history>2007-11-23 creation</history>
   <distribution_statement>Free</distribution_statement>
   <easternmost_longitude>120</easternmost_longitude>
   <title>Arctic Ocean Experiment 2001 AOE-2001.</title>
   <southernmost_latitude>79</southernmost_latitude>
   <datacollection_period from="2001-07-05" to="2001-08-21" />
   <abstract>
Arctic Ocean Experiment 2001 AOE-2001 was an icebreaker based field experiment 
with a target on the formation of low clouds in the central Arctic summer during 
July and August 2001. A main portion of the 2-moth experiment was a 3-week ice 
drift from 89 to 88 degN. Main components of the meteorology part of the 
experiment were surface-based remote- sensing observations, general meteorology 
observations (weather staion and soundings) and boundary-layer observations on 
the ice. For a complete review of the experiment and a full list of instruments, 
see Tjernstr&#246;m et al. 2004 ("The summertime Arctic atmosphere: Meteorological 
measurements during the Arctic Ocean Experiment (AOE-2001)" in Bulletin of the 
American Meteorological Society, 85, 1305 - 1321, and its on-line supplement 
"Experimental equipment: A supplement to The summertime Arctic atmosphere: 
Meteorological measurements during the Arctic Ocean Experiment (AOE-2001)"). 
Observations included in the dataset:
   Observations from 2D-wind sonic anemometer on the mast of Oden during AOE-2001. Beware of flow distortion from the ship.
   One-hour averaged cloud base observations from cloud base lidar and cloud radar during AOE-2001
   Instant cloud-top observations from S-band cloud radar operating in two modes, a low-range high-resolution and a high-range low-resolution mode, respectively, obtained during AOE-2001. The presented data is the highest cloud top altitude observed.
   Various meteorological observations from a mast placed on an ice-floe during AOE-2001
   Turbulence statistics from sonic anemometer at 15 meters on the mast averaged over 15 minute obtained during AOE-2001
   Turbulence statistics from sonic anemometer at 5 meters on the mast averaged over 15 minute obtained during AOE-2001
   Various meteorological observations from Odens weather station situated at 35 metres ASL during AOE-2001. Winds may be subject to considerable flow distortion. Precipitation is in arbitrary units.
   One-hour averaged precipitation from present-weather-sensor, which measures no. of precip particles falling past the sensor, during AOE-2001
   Wind profile data from 915 MHz profiler on foredeck of Oden obtained during AOE-2001
   Atmospheric baloon sounding data obtained during AOE-2001. The observations are interpolated to a fixed grid for plotting purposes.
   Measurements from the high range of the S-band cloud radar obtained during AOE-2001. The variables presented are radar reflectivity and hydro-meteor fall velocity.
   Measurements from the low range of the S-band cloud radar obtained during AOE-2001. The variables presented are radar reflectivity and hydro-meteor fall velocity.
   Temperature profiles measured by a scanning radiometer obtained during AOE-2001.
   Measurements from the sodar obtained during AOE-2001. Note that the altitude for each record varies in time.
   Observations 5 metres AGL from mobile ISSF PAM station 1 during AOE-2001.
   Turbulence observations 5 metres AGL from mobile ISSF PAM station 1 during AOE-2001.
   Observations 5 metres AGL from mobile ISSF PAM station 2 during AOE-2001.
   Turbulence observations 5 metres AGL from mobile ISSF PAM station 1 during AOE-2001.
   Observations 5 metres AGL from mobile ISSF PAM station 3 during AOE-2001.
   Turbulence observations 5 metres AGL from mobile ISSF PAM station 1 during AOE-2001.
   One-hour averaged visibility observations from back-scatter sensor during AOE-2001.
   </abstract>
   <institution>SU Stockholm University</institution>
   <variable>air_potential_temperature</variable>
   <variable>air_pressure</variable>
   <variable>air_temperature</variable>
   <variable>cloud_area_fraction</variable>
   <variable>cloud_base_altitude</variable>
   <variable>cloud_top_altitude</variable>
   <variable>dew_point_temperature</variable>
   <variable>downward_eastward_momentum_flux_in_air</variable>
   <variable>downward_heat_flux_in_air</variable>
   <variable>downward_northward_momentum_flux_in_air</variable>
   <variable>downward_water_vapor_flux_in_air_due_to_diffusion</variable>
   <variable>downwelling_longwave_flux_in_air</variable>
   <variable>downwelling_shortwave_flux_in_air</variable>
   <variable>eastward_wind</variable>
   <variable>magnitude_of_surface_downward_stress</variable>
   <variable>net_downward_longwave_flux_in_air</variable>
   <variable>net_downward_shortwave_flux_in_air</variable>
   <variable>northward_wind</variable>
   <variable>precipitation</variable>
   <variable>precipitation_flux</variable>
   <variable>Radar Reflectivity</variable>
   <variable>relative_humidity</variable>
   <variable>specific_humidity</variable>
   <variable>square_of_air_temperature</variable>
   <variable>square_of_eastward_wind</variable>
   <variable>square_of_northward_wind</variable>
   <variable>square_of_upward_air_velocity</variable>
   <variable>upward_air_velocity</variable>
   <variable>upwelling_longwave_flux_in_air</variable>
   <variable>upwelling_shortwave_flux_in_air</variable>
   <variable>visibility_in_air</variable>
   <variable>wind_from_direction</variable>
   <variable>wind_speed</variable>
   <quadtree_nodes>
23333
41134
144444
233314
322222
322224
322242
411111
411112
411113
411121
411123
411131
411133
411141
411143
411311
411312
411314
411321
411322
411324
411332
411433
413114
413121
413122
413123
413132
413211
413212
413214
413223
413232
413241
413243
413421
413423
413441
413443
431212
431214
431221
431232
431234
431344
431411
431412
431413
431431
431433
433122
433124
433141
433142
433143
433321
433323
433341
433343
433344
433433
433434
433443
   </quadtree_nodes>
</dataset>
